Guide to the Paul Kagan Utopian Communities Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Walter Millsap Papers, 1892-1970; Series I; 4.10' (13 boxes)
  - LLANO DEL RIO AND NEWLLANO
    - Writings by Others
      - Williams, Cecil. "Kid Kolony Christmas Story," holograph and typescript carbon, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - Williams, Robert K.
        - "Llano Social Life," early draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 64)
        - "Llano Social Life," intermediate draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
        - "Llano Social Life," later draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 66)
        - "Llano's Prospecting for Oil," early draft, typescript, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - Wooster, Ernest S.
        - "The Fresno Gang," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 68)
        - "A Man Must Fight," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 69)
        - "The Story of Llano," early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 70)
        - "The Story of Llano," later draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
        - Untitled. Partial history of Llano del Rio Colony, holograph draft, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 72)
        - Untitled. Fragments of a history of the Llano del Rio Colony, typescript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 73)
        - Untitled. History of the Llano del Rio Colony, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 74)
        - Untitled. Paragraphs from a manuscript by Ernest S. Wooster of Llano, typescript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 75)
        - Untitled. Section 1 of a history of the Llano del Rio Colony, typescript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
        - Untitled. Short essay on the end of the Llano Colony, early draft, typescript, corrected (Box 2, Folder 77)
        - Untitled. Short essay on the end of the Llano Colony, later draft, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Photographs and Postcards
      - People and landscapes at Llano del Rio. Photographs by M. Elkins, Llano Studio (Box 2, Folder 79-80)
      - People, landscapes and buildings at Llano del Rio (Box 3, Folder 81-89)
      - Contact prints made from glass plate negatives of Llano del Rio people, landscapes and buildings (Box 4, Folder 90)
      - Contact prints made from Alice Constance Austin's glass plate negatives: "Miadobe" and people (Box 4, Folder 91-92)
      - Contact prints of nitrate negatives of Alice Constance Austin: "Miadobe", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 93-95)
      - Fred Harvey postcards collected by Alice Constance Austin, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - Llano del Rio photograph albums, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 97-101)
      - Newllano people, landscapes and buildings, [1914], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 102-106)
      - Newllano people (postcards), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 107-109)
        In envelope addressed to Walter Millsap from E. J. Baker, Rigby, Idaho
      - "Louisiana Scenes" photograph album, 1919, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 110)
        Includes theater programs for the Colony Theatre and trade certificates for the Colony Commercial Depts. at back
      - Contact prints of nitrate negatives of Newllano people, landscapes and buildings, [1923] (Box 6, Folder 111-114)
    - Printed Material
      - Alice Constance Austin. Architectural drawings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 115)
        See also: Oversize, box 38, folder 689
      - Brotherhood Limavady, Co. Londonderry, 1928, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 116)
      - Buck, H. L. "Just a Correction" (broadside), n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 38, folder 690
      - Clippings: Llano del Rio, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 117)
      - Clippings: Newllano, 1930-40 (Box 6, Folder 118)
      - The Emancipator San Antonio, Texas, 1949 May (Box 6, Folder 119)
      - Industrial Democrat Leesville, Louisiana, 1935 Jun-Oct
        See: Oversize, box 38, folders 691-692
      - Meal ticket: Llano del Rio, California, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 120)
      - Reconstructionist Leesville, Louisiana, 1918 Aug (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - Scrapbook about Llano del Rio and Newllano, 1916-20 (Box 6, Folder 122)
        Includes clippings, checks, and a pamphlet, the original brief on the part of the Plaintiff in the case Llano del Rio Company of Nevada vs J. L. Scoggins
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets about Llano, 1924-61 (Box 6, Folder 123)
      - Theater programs for the Colony Theatre and trade certificates for the Colony Commercial Depts., 1919, n.d.
        See: "Louisiana Scenes" photograph album, box 5, folder 110
    - Walter Millsap Research Files
      - Inventory of Manuscripts Received from A. H. Moore, 1937 Aug 17 (Box 6, Folder 124)
      - Transcript of George T. Pickett's statements recorded by Walter Millsap, holograph, corrected, [1957] (Box 6, Folder 125)
      - Transcript of George T. Pickett's statements recorded by Walter Millsap, typescript, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 126)
      - Mellie Miller Calvert documents (photocopies), 1958 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Other Visual Material
      - Alice Constance Austin architectural drawings (photographic prints), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 128-129)
      - Map of the Llano Cooperative Colony, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 38, folder 693
      - Plaster flower inscribed on back, "A flower that grows in Alaska, modeled by Mary Fox, Llano, California", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 130)
      - Statue of Henry Dubb, Before Coming to Llano, and After Coming to Llano (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - COOPERATIVE WORK AFTER LLANO
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1924-30 (Box 6, Folder 132)
      - Correspondence, 1932-33 (Box 6, Folder 133)
      - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 134)
      - Correspondence, 1935-68 (Box 6, Folder 135)
      - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Documents
      - Promissory notes and receipts, 1925-45, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 137)
      - Inventories for United Co-Operative Industries, 1933-35 (Box 7, Folder 138)
      - Inventories for United Co-Operative Industries, 1936-41 (Box 7, Folder 139)
      - Inventories for United Co-Operative Industries (Box 7, Folder 140)
      - Addresses of California Cooperatives, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Writings by Walter Millsap
      - Essays for Epic News
        - Typescript carbon, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 142)
        - Typescript carbons, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 143)
          Includes chapter drafts of "The Land of the Other Way"
        - Holograph and typescript carbons, corrected (Box 7, Folder 144-145)
      - "The Land of the Other Way"
        - See also: Essays for Epic News, box 7, folder 143
        - Typescript, corrected, [1937] (Box 7, Folder 146)
        - Series of clippings bound together in a booklet (Box 7, Folder 147)
      - "Needles and the Corks"
        - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 148)
      - "The Reversal of Your Thinking"
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 149)
      - Miscellaneous essays, holographs, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Writings by Others
      - Clark, Tracy. "News Release on Cooperatives" typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Printed Material
      - Self-Help Cooperatives. An Introductory Study, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - State Production for Use Congress, [1935] (Box 7, Folder 153)
      - United Co-Operative Industries newsletter, 1933 Dec 30 (Box 7, Folder 154)
      - Ucopia [sic] Newsletter, 1955-65 (Box 7, Folder 155)
        Sent to Mellie Miller Calvert
      - Other cooperatives' newsletters, 1937-38 (Box 7, Folder 156)
        Sebastopol Consumer's Cooperative Association, Inc. and Southwest Cooperative Society
      - Clippings, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 157)
      - Fragment of instructions for electric blanket sold by United Co-Operative Industries (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Correspondence
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1911-16 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1917-18 (Box 7, Folder 160)
        Includes 5 postcards with photographs of Llano del Rio, California on front
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 161)
        Includes 2 postcards with photographs of Newllano, Louisiana on front
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 162)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1922-26 (Box 7, Folder 163)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1927-28 (Box 7, Folder 164)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 165)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1930-32 (Box 8, Folder 166)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1934-39 (Box 8, Folder 167)
      - Walter Millsap and others, 1952-70 (Box 8, Folder 168)
      - Walter Millsap and others (Box 8, Folder 169)
      - Leander W. Millsap and others, 1920-35 (Box 8, Folder 170)
      - Cara Millsap and others, 1927-36 (Box 8, Folder 171)
      - Cara Millsap and others, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 172)
      - Cara Millsap and others, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 173)
      - Cara Millsap and others (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Documents
      - Record of Family Traits (filled out) and related writings and printed material from the Eugenics Record Office, 1914-15 (Box 8, Folder 175)
      - Exams and statements for correspondence course in Character Analysis, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 176)
      - Receipts and statements, 1916-31 (Box 8, Folder 177)
      - Otis Intelligence Tests (not filled out), 1920-21 (Box 8, Folder 178)
      - Agreements, statements, and other documents relating to Gast property, 1926-29 (Box 8, Folder 179)
      - Address file, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 180)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 181)
      - Unidentified author. Inventory of dining room, n.y. Dec 17 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Writings by Walter Millsap
      - "A Life Time of Trial and Error," typescript, corrected (Box 8, Folder 183)
        See also: Oversize, box 38, folder 694
        See also: Broadside cabinet, folder 826
      - "Magnetism and Life," typescript copy (Box 8, Folder 184)
      - "Millsap's Picture School," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Writings by Others
      - Harman, Gertrude C. "Control of Life Force," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - Photographs and Postcards
      - Walter Millsap, buildings and landscapes. Photographs by H. Cook of Woodland, California, [1892], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 187-191)
        Includes a tintype
      - Walter Millsap and others (Box 9, Folder 192-194)
        Photographs by Harold McCurry, Commercial Fotografer [sic], Sacramento; Hemenway, Vacaville, Cal.; J. C. Shinkle, Woodland, Cal.
      - People and landscapes (Box 9, Folder 195-196)
        Photographs signed "L.W.M."
      - People, [1911] (Box 10, Folder 197)
        Photographs by J. E. D. Baldwin, Rembrandt Studio, Sacramento; Soracco, California Art Studio
      - Miscellaneous photographs: people, landscapes, buildings, dogs, and tools, [1909-56] (Box 10, Folder 198-208)
      - Miscellaneous photographs: people, landscapes, buildings, dogs, and tools, [1909-56] (Box 11, Folder 209-215)
      - Contact prints of nitrate negatives of miscellaneous photographs: people, landscapes, buildings, dogs, [1923], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 216)
      - Contact prints of glass plate negatives of people, places, and tools (Box 11, Folder 217)
      - Postcards of San Francisco and New Orleans (Box 12, Folder 218)
    - Printed Material
      - Advertisement for Walter Millsap's "Squeezit" Wrench, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 219)
      - The American Unit Los Angeles, 1932 Sep 21 (Box 12, Folder 220)
      - The Call New York, New York, 1943-44 (Box 12, Folder 221-222)
        See also: Oversize, box 38, folders 695-697
      - Common Sense, 1954 May, Jun
        See: Oversize, box 38, folder 698
      - Commonwealth College Fortnightly Vol. 12, No. 8. Mena, Arkansas, 1936 Apr 15 (Box 12, Folder 223)
      - The Dan Smoot Report Dallas, Texas, 1962 Jan 8 (Box 12, Folder 224)
      - Friday New York, New York, 1940-41
        See: Oversize, box 38, folders 699-700
        See: Oversize, box 39, folders 701-702
      - Human Culture Digest Los Angeles, 1946, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 225)
      - Life Science Hollywood, Calif., 1966 Jan-Feb
        See: Oversize, box 39, folder 703
      - The Lookout Seattle, Washington, 1966 Aug, Oct (Box 12, Folder 226)
      - Mailings from the Esoteric Publishing Company, [1898-1916] (Box 12, Folder 227)
      - Patent for Millsap's Hand-Printer for Mailer-Strips and Proof-Sheets, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 228)
      - Sir Thomas More. Utopia, printed, with paper wrapper, title page lacking, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 229)
      - Pamphlets
        - Agriculture, [1920]-38 (Box 12, Folder 230)
        - Building houses, 1929-[60] (Box 12, Folder 231)
        - Communism, 1934-54 (Box 12, Folder 232-233)
          Also includes a broadsheet
          See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 704
        - Herbert C. Holdridge, 1951, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 234)
          See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 705
        - International peace, [1928]-62 (Box 12, Folder 235)
        - House Un-American Activities Committee, [1957-63] (Box 12, Folder 236)
          Also includes a broadside
          See also: Broadside cabinet, folder 827
        - Socialism, 1930-37 (Box 12, Folder 237)
        - Korean War, [1950]-53 (Box 12, Folder 238)
          See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 706
        - Music, including sheet music, 1917-51 (Box 12, Folder 239)
          See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 707
        - Universal Pantheism, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 240)
        - Biographies of Americans, 1927-34 (Box 13, Folder 241)
      - Sinclair, Upton. I, Governor of California and The Lie Factory Starts (Box 13, Folder 242)
      - Soviet Russia Today New York, New York, 1936-45 (Box 13, Folder 243-246)
      - U. S. Farm News Des Moines, Iowa, 1965 Jan
        See: Oversize, box 39, folder 708
      - West Coast Sailors San Francisco, 1948 Jun 11
        See: Oversize, box 39, folder 709
      - Other miscellaneous pamphlets, ephemera and newspapers gathered by Millsap, 1920-68 (Box 13, Folder 247-250)
        See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 710
        See also: Broadside cabinet, folder 828
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1937-45 (Box 13, Folder 251-252)
- William and Lucille Riker Papers, 1876-1969; Series II; 1.45' (4 boxes)
  Series II, William and Lucille Riker Papers, is organized into two subseries: Holy City, and Personal Papers
  - HOLY CITY
    - Correspondence
      - William Riker and others, 1943-63, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 253)
      - Irvin B. Fisher and others, 1925-62 (Box 14, Folder 254)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1943, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 255)
    - Documents
      - Certificates belonging to Holy City inhabitants, 1959, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 256)
      - Financial statements, income tax form, receipts belonging to Joseph Albert, 1961-66 (Box 14, Folder 257)
      - Address cards, account book belonging to unidentified people, 1963-65 (Box 14, Folder 258)
    - Writings
      - Writings and paste-ups for Holy City newsletters, with holograph drafts, drawings, and some illustrations colored in with crayon (Box 14, Folder 259-264)
        See also: Oversize, box 40, folder 717
      - Writings and paste-ups for Holy City newsletters, with holograph drafts, drawings, and some illustrations colored in with crayon (Box 15, Folder 265-268)
    - Photographs and Postcards
      - Holy City people and buildings (Box 15, Folder 269)
        Includes some photographs with stamp of Irvin B. Fisher
      - Contact prints of nitrate negatives of Holy City people and buildings (Box 15, Folder 270)
      - Perfect Christian Divine Way School of Mastery in San Francisco (Box 15, Folder 271)
      - Perfect Christian Divine Way School of Mastery in San Francisco (cyanotypes) (Box 15, Folder 272)
    - Other Visual Material
      - Banners (18) with inspirational sayings, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 41, folders 742-759
      - Illustrations for talks and displays (Box 15, Folder 273-275)
      - Posters (2) advertising P.C.D.W. doctrine, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 39, folders 711-712
      - Watercolor poster advertising P.C.D.W. doctrine, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 41, folder 760
      - Poster in crayon: "Gentile, Jew, To Control, Use and Beautify the Earth and the Fullness Thereof"
        See: Broadside cabinet, folder 829
      - Sign: "P.C.D.W. School of Mastery", n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 40, folder 718
      - Plywood sign advertising the New World Plan, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 42, folder 761
      - Sign advertising Perfect Christian Divine Way doctrine
        See: Oversize, box 40, folder 719
    - Printed Material
      - Blank letterhead, envelope, and labels (Box 15, Folder 276)
      - Christmas card from Riker, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 277)
      - Plan-O-Graphic printing plates for newsletters, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 40, folder 720
      - Page proofs of newsletters, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 278-279)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - William Riker
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 280)
      - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 281-282)
      - Correspondence, 1948-64 (Box 16, Folder 283)
      - Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 284)
      - Legal files: William E. Riker vs. Melvin Belli, and associated suits, 1943, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 286)
      - Receipts, certificates, and statement of account belonging to William Riker, 1916-69 (Box 16, Folder 287)
      - Clippings about William Riker, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 288)
      - Kemp, Jack E. "Love Cult A La Hitler" in Sensation, 1941 Dec (Box 16, Folder 289)
      - Miscellaneous books belonging to William and Lucille Riker, 1876-95 (Box 16, Folder 290-292)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets and newsletters gathered by William Riker, 1943-63 (Box 16, Folder 293)
        See also: Oversize, box 40, folder 721
      - Photographs of William and Lucille Riker and others (Box 16, Folder 294)
        Photographs by Leon's Photo Studio, San Francisco; and Hartsook, San Francisco and other California locations
        See also: Oversize, box 40, folders 722-729
      - Drawings of William Riker, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 40, folders 730-731
    - Lucille Riker
      - Correspondence, 1930-44 (Box 16, Folder 294)
      - Receipt, song contract, and copyright registration belonging to Lucille Riker, 1927, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 295)
      - "Please Don't Leave Me Daddy." Words and Music by Lucille Riker (Box 17, Folder 296)
      - Writings: Song lyrics, short story "Mother Be A Man", 1930-31 (Box 17, Folder 297)
        See also: Lucille Riker Correspondence, box 16, folder 294a
      - Books belonging to Lucille Riker
        See: Box 16, folders 290-292
      - Photographs of Lucille Riker
        See: Box 16, folder 294, and Oversize, box 40, folders 722-729
    - Others
      - Fisher, Irvin B., various essays, 1963, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 298)
      - Photographs of unidentified people and buildings (Box 17, Folder 299)
- John and Agnes Varian Papers, 1893-[1935]; Series III; 0.2' (1 box)
  Series III, John and Agnes Varian Papers, is organized into one subseries, Halcyon
  - HALCYON
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1893-1901 (Box 18, Folder 300)
      - Correspondence, 1905-11 (Box 18, Folder 301)
      - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 18, Folder 302-303)
      - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 304)
      - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 305)
      - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 306)
      - Correspondence fragments (Box 18, Folder 307)
    - Writings
      - "The Cross" (poem), 1910 May (Box 18, Folder 308)
      - "Rallying Cry of the Red Ray" (song), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 309)
      - "The Right To Be or Not To Be," signed, "Red Star (W.H.D.)", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 310)
      - Notes on teachings, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 311)
    - Printed Material
      - Calendar, "Compliments of the Season" by Varian & Harrison, Halcyon, Calif. for 1936, [1935]
        See: Oversize, box 40, folder 732
      - The Electro-Medical News Vol. 1, No. 2. Halcyon, California, n.d.
        See: Oversize, box 40, folder 733
      - Pamphlets on Temple teachings, 1919, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 312)
      - Playbill for "Mystery Play with Musical Setting", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 313)
      - Varian, Agnes. The Inner Voice, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 314)
      - Clippings, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 315)
    - Other Papers
      - Receipts, 1896-1916 (Box 18, Folder 316)
      - People and buildings, 1915-32, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 317-318)
        One photograph by Allen & Metzler, San Luis Obispo
        See also: Oversize, box 40, folder 734
- Paul Kagan Research Files, 1845-1980; Series IV; 4.3' (16 boxes)
  Series IV, Paul Kagan Research Files, is organized into seventeen subseries: The Farm, Fountaingrove, Halcyon, Holy City, Icaria Speranza, International Re-Educational Foundation, Kaweah, Krotona and Ojai Valley, Lama Foundation, Llano del Rio and Newllano, Pisgah Grande, Point Loma, Rosicrucians, Self-Realization Fellowship, Tassajara Zen Mountain Center, Vedanta Society of Southern California, and Other Communes.
  - THE FARM
    - Beatnik Bell Phone List, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 319)
    - Clipping: "Trippin' and Preachin' the Basics," San Francisco Chronicle" (Box 19, Folder 320)
    - Pamphlets, books, and broadsheets published by The Book Publishing Company at The Farm, 1974-76 (Box 19, Folder 321-323)
      See also: Oversize, box 39, folder 713
  - FOUNTAINGROVE
    - Photographs
      Vintage Prints
      - Portraits. Photographer: Imai, San Francisco, 1904, n.d.
      - Portraits, landscapes and buildings. Photographer: J. Ross, Santa Rosa, Cal., 1896-1916 (Box 19, Folder 326-328)
      - Portraits. Photographer: Uchiyama, San Francisco, 1899-1902 (Box 19, Folder 329)
      - Portraits and landscapes. Photographers: Piggott, Santa Rosa, Cal.; F. O. Haussler, Oakland, Cal.; Taber, San Francisco; Tsuji Photo Studio, Oakland, Cal., 1900-25, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 330)
      - Fountaingrove people, buildings, and landscapes, [1906-27], n.d. (Box 20, Folder 331-337)
      - Fountaingrove people, buildings, and landscapes, [1873-1927] (Box 21, Folder 338-347)
        See also: Oversize, box 40, folders 735-737
      - [Theodore Roosevelt?], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 348)
      - Schooner, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 349)
      - Santa Rosa and San Francisco, [1906], n.d. (Box 22, Folder 350)
      - Album containing portraits, n.d.
        Photographers: Piggott, Santa Rosa, Cal.; J. Ross, Santa Rosa, Cal.; J. H. Peters, San Francisco; H. Kempvanee, Santa Rosa, Cal.; Taber, San Francisco; T. J. Bruce, Marshall, Texas; Z. Yamabe, San Francisco
        See: Oversize, box 43, folder 762
      - Paul Kagan's Photographs
        - Views of Fountaingrove: positives, 1970
          See: Oversize, box 40, folders 738-741
        - Views of Fountaingrove: negatives, [1970-74] (Box 22, Folder 351)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives From Others
        - For reference use only. May not be reproduced
        - Copy prints and negative from the Bancroft Library (Box 22, Folder 352)
        - Copy prints and negative from the California State Library (Box 22, Folder 353)
        - Copy prints and negatives from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Columbia University (Box 22, Folder 354)
        - Copy prints and negatives from the Huntington Library (Box 22, Folder 355)
      - Copy Prints and Negatives
        - May include copy prints from vintage photographs above
        - Copy prints from other and unidentified sources (Box 22, Folder 356-359)
        - Copy negatives from other and unidentified sources (Box 23, Folder 360-362)
    - Printed Material
      - Alaas, Jim, "A Brief History of Kanaye Nagasawa of the Fountaingrove Vineyard" (photocopy), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 363)
      - LeBaron, Gaye, "Fountaingrove," Golden Gate North, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 364)
      - The Markham Review. Published by the Horrmann Library of Wagner College, no. 4 (Box 23, Folder 365)
      - Fountaingrove Ranch stationery, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 366)